Guide to Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Edward H. Litchfield, Administrative Files, 1956-1965 UA.2.10.1956-1965
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- General Office Files, 1955-1965; II.
  - Meeting of Scaife and Leader regarding financing of Health Professions Building, Scholarships and Grants, Ford Foundation Grant, September 1956 (Box 149, Folder 1261)
  - Proposed Policies for Disciplines, Memo: Procedural Relations between the Board of Trustees and the University Administration, - Excerpt from Minutes of Board of Trustees, Authorization to Negotiate with the General State Authority, August 1956 (Box 149, Folder 1262)
  - Organization and Job Description Manual University of Pittsburgh, Procedure on Contract Approvals Signatures, Purchase of Schenely Park Hotel and Apartments, July 1956 (Box 149, Folder 1263)
  - By-Laws of the Board of Trustees, Spring 1956 Issue of Pitt about Sarah Mellon Scaife Radiation Laboratory, Letter from the Ford Foundation regarding grant of $965,000, April 1956-June 1956 (Box 149, Folder 1264)
  - New policies and organization, Autumn 1955 issue of Pitt: appointment of Litchfield, Copy of Resolution Adopted by Board of Trustees Autumn, June 1955-November 1955 (Box 150, Folder 1265)
  - Budget Requests, 1963-1967 (Box 150, Folder 1266-1269)
  - Supplies, 1964-1965 (Box 150, Folder 1270-1271)
  - Books for Chancellor's Office, 1962-1963 (Box 151, Folder 1272)
  - Administration Listings, Advisory Boards - Regional Programs; Alumni Council; Presbyterian - University Board of Trustees; NASA / INDUSTRY / University; Magee Womens Hospital; Hospital Council of Western Pennsylvania; Health Center Hospital - Service Corporation; Joint Trustees - Health Center; Eye and Ear Hospital; Education, School of; Ecuador; Council of Deans; Children's Hospital; Child Guidance Center; Central Blood Bank; Board of Trustees; Law, School of; Magee Women's Hospital; NASA/Industry/University; Presbyterian University Board of Trustees; Regional Programs; University Senate; Womens Association; Western Psychiatric Institute (Box 151, Folder 1273)
    Each of the following titles contains correspondence,or other material by or about that organization
  - Procedure, Deaths to be reported (Box 151, Folder 1274)
  - EHL awaiting answers (Box 151, Folder 1275)
  - Bailie awaiting answers and hold for future (Box 151, Folder 1276)
  - Speeches; EHL (Box 151, Folder 1277)
  - Dr. Litchfield's Inaugural Address -, May 1957 (Box 151, Folder 1278)
  - Personal expense vouchers (Box 151, Folder 1279)
  - Requisitions, 1955-1963 (Box 151, Folder 1280-1281)
  - Rentals, service charges, stockroom supplies, work requests (Box 152, Folder 1282)
  - Book Purchases, Outside Orders, Printing Requisitions (Box 152, Folder 1283)
  - GSA 'Project Reports', Miscellaneous A-Z, Magazines, Slides, Supplies (Box 152, Folder 1284)
  - Reports: Development Plans and Projects in the College of Academic Disciplines and Development Plans and Projects for the Social and Engineering Professions, 1963-1965 (Box 152, Folder 1285)
  - Financial Survey and Analysis the University of Pittsburgh, 1955-1965 (Box 152, Folder 1286)
  - Proposal to the NSF for a Five Year Science Development Program, 1964 (Box 152, Folder 1287)
  - Proposed organic law for state-relationship between the University of Pittsburgh and the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania (Box 152, Folder 1288)
  - Tax aspects of giving to University; Ten year report to Community,"Cathedral" memorial poem to Dr. S. C. Crawford by Dr. Lawrence Lee; Organization of the University and "Spin Off", 1955-1965 (Box 152, Folder 1289)
  - Ecuador Project - 2nd report, 1963 (Box 152, Folder 1290)
  - University of San Carlos and University of Pittsburgh, 1963 (Box 153, Folder 1291)
  - Governor's Council of Science and Technology, report, 1966 (Box 153, Folder 1292)
  - NASA Proposal (Box 153, Folder 1293)
    Includes Organizational Chart from October 1961.
  - Long-range development plan, February 15, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1294)
  - Selected Policy Papers and Statements, October 10, 1961 (Box 153, Folder 1295)
  - Long term financing program, January 21, 1963 (Box 153, Folder 1296)
  - General Plan for University Development, 1957 (Box 153, Folder 1297)
  - Five year plans for Biological Science Department of Chemistry, Department of Physics, Crystallography Laboratory, 1961-1962 (Box 153, Folder 1298)
  - Policy Paper #1, 1957-1958 (Box 153, Folder 1299)
    General Principles for the long range plan
  - Program for the College of the Academic Disciplines at the University of Pittsburgh (Box 154, Folder 1300)
  - Campus Development Plan including Map showing alternative research areas, 1961 (Box 154, Folder 1301)
    Copy of letter from Dr. E. H. Litchfield to Mr. Gwilym A. Price, Chairman of the Board Westinghouse Electric Corporation, Oakland Corporation pamphlet
  - Oakland Development Corporation, 1961 (Box 154, Folder 1302-1305)
  - Press Releases on Oakland Urban Renewal, Articles of Incorporation for the Oakland Corporation, 1962 (Box 154, Folder 1306)
  - Form of Resolution to be Adopted by Governing Body of Institutions and Corporations Subscribing for Stock in Oakland Corporations, 1962 (Box 154, Folder 1307)
  - Biographical sketch of Frederick Maurice Smith, June 1962 (Box 154, Folder 1308)
    Research: 'The Key to Pittsburgh's Economic Growth,' and address by Chancellor E. H. Litchfield, Pennsylvania Economy League (Research Park); 'Possible Courses of Action to Increase the Opportunity of Faculty to Live in Oakland';Photo copy of letter to Leland P. Deck; Photo copy of Minutes of the Tumble Run Meeting of on Oakland and Faculty Residents; sent to Leland R. Deck from Stanton C. Crawford; Photo copy of letter to Dr. Karl H. Oermann from L. L. Monnett, Jr regarding Recreation-playground study in Oakland area; Minutes of the Tumble Run Meeting of July 30, 1962; Photo copies of articles on Faculty Housing for the University of Pittsburgh; Organization Chart Oakland Corporation; Proposal to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration by the University of Pittsburgh; Congratulatory letter from University Secretary Stanton C. Crawford to Litchfield regarding NASA proposal; Letter to Dr. John T. Holloway, Chief University Programs, The National Aeronautics and Space Administration, Washington, D. C.
  - "Toward Higher Ground" A Five-Year Report on Progress of the University of Pittsburgh,;delivered by Edward H. Litchfield at the University's annual alumni convocation; during events which marked the 175th Anniversary of the University; Other files, 1957-1962 (Box 155, Folder 1309)
    Organizing for Spin-Off; Letters, clippings, and memorandum for meeting with the heads of Pittsburgh institutions of higher education and of Mellon Institute to meet at Carnegie Tech on Oct. 24, 1962; Clipping regarding appointments and elections for Oakland Corporation attached to release from Russell R. Jalbert "This is an Urban Area" booklet highlighting projects of the Oakland Corporation for Panther Hollow, Nov. 27, 1962.
  - Litchfield Inauguration budgets and plans, 1956-1957 (Box 155, Folder 1310)
  - Board of Trustees - Correspondence, Dr. A. M. Scaife, 1952-1955 (Box 155, Folder 1311-1312)
  - Budget Matters - Correspondence and various Budget Material, 1963-1964 (Box 155, Folder 1313-1315)
  - Reports on Tumble Run Conference, June, July, August 1964 (Box 155, Folder 1316)
  - Personnel Matters [RESTRICTED] (Box 155, Folder 1317)